A Guide to the Hanksin family papers, 1907-1929
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Hanksin family papers, 1907-1929
The Library of Virginia
51286
.675 cu. ft. and 2 boxes
Hankins family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ann Johann of Richmond, Virginia.
Biographical/Historical Information
Mary Virginia Hankins (27 August 1886-26 July 1980) and Charles Oliver Hankins (26 April 1888-July 1968) were the daughter and son of Oliver Alexander Hankins (1844-1929) and Mary Louise Pleasants Hankins(ca. 1847-1894). Mary Hankins worked as a book keeper and stenographer. Charles Hankins worked in the family sheet metal business, becoming proprietor upon his father's death. Charles Hankins served in Company K, 318th Infantry, during World War I, and was promoted to corporal 13 September 1918. On 25 October 1918 he became a sergeant in Company L, 318th Infantry. Virginia and Charles Hankins lived with their other brother and sister, William Pleasants Hankins (1883-1946) and Ellenor A. Hankins (1884-1977). They are all buried in Hollywood Cemetery in Richmond, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1907-1929, of the Hankins family consisting of correspondence, 1918-1919, 1928, regarding military service in World War I, payment of taxes, weddings, and an automobile accident; abstracts, contrats, deeds, and other papers between Ginter Park Realty and Charles O. Hankins (1888-1968) and Mary V. Hankins (1886-1980) for real property in Ginter Park Terrace; miscellaneous papers, 1907-1929, contains certificates, notes, orders, pamphlets, poems, receipts, and other papers regarding World War I, Mary Hankins first grade teaching certificate, flowers, groceries, cars, the Moravian church, Buffalo, New York, and Niagara Falls; and photographs of the Hankins family and friends.
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Real property papers, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Real property papers, 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Real property papers, 1916, 1918 (1920) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Real property papers, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- General papers--note on politics, note on disabled soldiers, Moravian church, quiz Flower Romance, grocery order, cream ad, We Shall Not Sleep (In Flanders Fields), teaching certificate, receipts, clippings, wrapper, and pamphlets, 1907-1929 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Photographs (folder 1 of 8) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Photographs (folder 2 of 8) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Photographs (folder 3 of 8) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Photographs (folder 4 of 8) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Photographs (folder 5 of 8) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Photographs (folder 6 of 8) (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Photographs (folder 7 of 8) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Photographs (folder 8 of 8) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Photograph--Company K, 318th Infantry at Camp Lee (Box 2)
- Photograph--Richmond men at Camp Lee (Box 2)